你答应要嫁给乔伊？
You said you'd marry Joey?
你要知道我可是累坏了 当时我很情绪化
Okay,you have to realize,I was exhausted,I was emotional.
任何人求婚，我都会答应的
I would have said yes to anybody.
就像上次你向我求婚一样
Like that time when you and I got married.
我控制不了自己
I'm not helping.
你才刚生下我们的小孩 却答应要嫁给他？
So you said yes to him,and you just had our baby?
没错，而且按照习俗 父亲应该要送母亲一个礼物的
That is right. And traditionally,the daddy gives the mommy a present.
但是我不打算跟你计较
But I am prepared to let that go.
所以当我过来看你 是否愿意重新来过…
So when I came here to see if you wanted to maybe start things up again..
你已经跟我最要好的朋友订婚了？
you were engaged to my best friend?
嗯…
Well..
真的吗？
Really?
我以为钱德才是你最要好的朋友
I thought Chandler was your best friend.
钱德是我的老朋友 乔伊是我…不！
Well,Chandler's my oldest friend. Joey's my.. No!
嘿，我要走了 进来说一声再见
Hey,I'm gonna take off. I just wanted to say goodbye.
瑞秋答应要嫁给你？
Rachel said she'd marry you?
我走错房间了，不好意思
This isn't the right room. Sorry,folks.
艾玛哭不停
The.One.Where.Emma.Cries
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
主演：寇妮考克斯
主演：丽莎库卓
主演：麦特勒布兰
主演：马修派瑞
主演：大卫修蒙
（我是男生！）
我不想否定你，所以我要说 你挑的标语大部分都是很棒的
I don't want to be negative. So I'll say most of the signs you bought are good.
“我是女生！”卖完了 但是我可以处理一下的
No,they ran out of "It's a Girl!" But I can fix this one.
（我不是男生！）
瞧？怎样？
See? Huh?
真性感
So sexy.
-亲爱的？ -什么？
- Honey? - Yeah?
-亲爱的，你何不去躺下休息呢？ -没关系
- Honey,why don't you lie down? - It's okay.
罗斯跟瑞秋很快就要回来了 然后我得去办公室
Ross and Rachel will be back soon,and then I gotta go to the office.
这是从我嘴里长的吗？
Am I producing them?
-你为什么这样累呢？ -我昨晚无法入睡
- Why are you so tired? - I couldn't sleep last night.
我很担心今天的大型部门会议
I started worrying about this big divisional meeting I have today.
我越是担心 越是没有办法入睡
The more I worried,the more I couldn't sleep.
你知道的，我会想 如果现在睡着，我顶多睡六小时
You know,and then I was,like,"If I fall asleep now,I'll get six hours' sleep.
但是如果我现在睡着 我顶多睡五个小时
But if I fall asleep now,I'll get five hours' sleep."
无论我怎么试，就是睡不着
No matter what I did,I couldn't fall asleep.
你知道你应该做什么吗？
You know what you should've done?
对你自己讲那个小故事
Told yourself that little story.
-嗨 -嘿
- Hi. - Hey.
-欢迎回家 -嗨
- Welcome home. - Hi.
标示是菲比做的
Phoebe did the signs.
你们，真是太谢谢你们了
You guys,thanks for doing this.
瞧瞧大家送来的礼物
Look at all that stuff people sent.
喔，我的天啊 这正是每个母亲所需要的
Oh,my gosh. Look,there's something every mother needs.
一个挤爆整间公寓的大型黑猩猩娃娃
A giant,stuffed gorilla that takes up the entire apartment.
真搞不懂有些人在想…？ 你们大家，我真是太喜欢了
What are people think..? You guys,I love it.
嘿，罗斯在哪呢？
Hey,so where's Ross?
他在楼下把东西搬出计程车
He's downstairs getting the stuff out of the cab.
-他还在气我们两个吗？ -气你多过于我
- Is he still mad at us? - Well,you more than me.
他总不能一直跟我生气 我才刚生下他的小孩耶
But he can't stay too mad at me. I mean,I just had his baby.
太不公平了，我又不会生
That's not fair. I can't do that.
我不知道他上来时 你应不应该在场
I'm not sure you should be here when he comes up.
我也不认为我该在场 但有人跟我说罗斯应该已经释怀了
I didn't think I should be here either. But somebody said he'd be over it.
嘿，我怎么会知道呢？ 我只是想要买只大一点的黑猩猩啊
Hey,what do I know? I wanted to get a bigger gorilla.
我们在芝加哥、纽约 与伦敦的业绩都很扎实
The numbers we're seeing in Chicago,New York and London are solid.
但是我们许多分公司已经呈现衰退
But many of our field offices have reported disappointing yields.
波士顿衰退、亚特兰大衰退 休士顿衰退
Boston is down. Atlanta is down. Houston is down.
我可以一直念下去 但是为了不要让你们觉得无趣
I could go on and on. But instead of boring you..
我直接说明我的四十二点计划好了
I'll go straight to my 42-point plan.
华特
Walter.
她真是太可爱了
She's just so cute.
我真想咬下她的耳朵 当成糖果一样吸
I just want to bite her ear off and use it as a sucking candy.
菲比
Phoebe.
但是我可以把这些小脚 放到面饼里面
But I could take one of those little feet and put it in a pita pocket.
-好了，我把大部分的东西都放好了 -喔，太好了，奶嘴呢？
- Okay. I put most of the stuff away. - Oh,great. The pacifiers?
-在柜橱里 -打嗝围兜？
- It's in the cupboard. - The burping cloths?
-毛巾橱里 -尿布？
- Linen closet. - The diapers?
在医院
In the hospital.
-哇，你们有间医院？真酷 -不，我把尿布忘在医院了
- Wow,you guys got a hospital? Fancy. - No,I left the diapers at the hospital.
在袋子里面还有一些 但是我现在就出去多买一些
There's some in the bag,but I'll run out and get some more.
好的，谢谢
All right,thanks.
经过咖啡屋时可以帮我买个松饼吗？
Could you stop at the coffeehouse and get me a muffin?
-当然，什么口味的？ -让我想想
- Sure. What kind? - Let me think.
我要什么口味呢？
What do I want?
请你慢慢想 这是非常重要的决定，不像是…
Please,take your time. It's an important decision,not like..
决定要嫁给谁那样简单 这是松饼喔
say,I don't know,deciding to marry someone. This is about a muffin.
-蓝莓的 -好吧，蓝莓
- Blueberry. - Blueberry it is.
谢谢你
Thank you.
哇，他还在记恨，对吧？
Wow,he's not letting this go,is he?
天啊，你觉得这会持续多久呢？
God,how long do you think that's gonna last?
我不知道，他倒是对“我们当时分手了” 那件事，释怀的挺快的
I don't know. He got over the "We were on a break" thing quickly.
你们知道吗？ 我现在无法去担心那件事
You know what,I can't worry about it right now.
因为我有了这个可爱的小宝贝
Because I've got the cutie little baby.
我无法相信我是这样的爱她 我是说，我太爱她了
I can't believe how much I love her. I mean,I can't get enough of her.
就像现在，我好想她 我真的好想她
Like,right now? I miss her. I actually miss her.
你知道吗？她就在这里
You know,that's her?
我知道，但是她在睡觉
I know. I know,but she's sleeping.
如果她醒着，我就可以看她扭来扭去的
It's not like when she's awake and I can see her stretch and wiggle.
喔，天啊，看到她打哈欠没？
Oh,my God,have you seen her yawn?
-真是太可爱了 -真的是
- It's so cute. - I know.
你们觉得她什么时候会醒来？
When do you think she's gonna wake up?
她告诉我，如果她十一点还没醒 要我打电话给她
She told me to ring her if she's not up by 11.
她有个面试要去
She has a job interview.
好的，但是当她打哈欠时 乌云都消散了
Okay,but the clouds part when she yawns.
天啊，瞧她睡着的样子 我好爱她
God,look at her sleeping. I love her so much.
-我想我要把她吵醒 -瑞秋，不要
- I think I'm gonna wake her up. - Rach,no.
你永远都不应该吵醒熟睡的婴儿
You know,you're never supposed to wake a sleeping baby.
我可以高兴怎样做就怎样做 她是我生的
Well,I can do whatever I want. I made her.
来吧，小女孩 是的，嗨，艾玛，嗨
Come on,little girl. Yes. Hello,Emma. Hello. Hi.
我应该说我早就告诉过你了 但是她已经帮我说了
Well,I would say I told you so,but she's kind of doing that for me.
我很抱歉，妈咪很抱歉 再睡吧
I'm sorry. Mommy's so sorry. Go back to sleep.
再睡觉吧
Go back to sleep.
-这真是令人心疼，不是吗？ -没错
- It breaks your heart,doesn't it? - It really does.
你认为我们还要呆多久？
How long do you think we have to stay?
好了，如果每个人都各就各位 那就搞定了
Okay,if everyone's onboard,it's settled.
钱德？
Chandler?
-钱德？ -怎样
- Chandler? - Yeah.
你要就位了吗？
Are you onboard?
是的
Yes.
那么问题就解决了 钱德会负责我们在土尔沙的办公室
Well,then problem solved. Chandler will run our office in Tulsa.
你会喜欢奥克拉荷马的
You're gonna love Oklahoma.
好了，我们已经喂过她了 换过尿布、帮她打嗝了…
All right. We already tried feeding her,changing her,burping her..
试试看这个 回去听听菲比的话吧
Try this one. "Go back in time and listen to Phoebe."
-好了，试试看这个 -什么？
- All right,here's something. - What?
这里说试着把婴儿抱起，贴近身体…
It says to try holding the baby close to your body..
然后快速的左右摇
and then swing her rapidly from side to side.
好的
Okay.
太有效了！
It worked!
不，只是让她吐了一点奶
No. Just stopped to throw up a little bit.
莫妮卡，我应该怎么办呢？
Mon,what am I gonna do?
已经好几个小时了 它就是哭个不停
It's been hours,and it won't stop crying.
-她，瑞秋，不是它，是她 -是喔，我可不太确定了
- She,Rach. Not it. She. - Yeah. I'm not so sure.
-喔，我的天啊，我快疯了 -是啊，说得没错
- Oh,my God,I'm losing my mind. - Yeah,no kidding.
这正好证明跟罗斯做爱 绝对没有好事会发生
All right,this just proves no good can come from having sex with Ross!
嘿，甘瑟，我要外带几个蓝莓松饼
Hey,Gunther. Can I get a couple of blueberry muffins to go?
-尿布，是吧？ -是的
- Diapers,huh? - Yep.
我猜瑞秋生下你的小孩了
So I guess Rachel had your baby?
-是啊，你能相信吗？ -不能
- Yep. Can you believe it? - Nope.
首先我就不能相信 她竟然会跟你上床
I can't even believe she slept with you in the first place.
你是说，像是…
You mean,like..
嘿
Hey.
我知道你生我的气 但是我们必须谈一谈
I know you're pissed at me,but we have to talk about this.
事实上我们不需要
Actually,we don't.
随便，但是我要说 技术上而言，我并没有做错什么
Fine. Okay. But I gotta say,technically,I didn't even do anything wrong.
什么？你并没有做错什么？
What? You didn't do anything wrong?
-我说是技术上而言 -好的
- I said I didn't technically. - Okay.
我们暂时不管你“不小心”…
Let's put aside the fact that you "accidentally"..
捡起我祖母的戒指，然后又 “不小心”跟瑞秋求婚
picked up my grandmother's ring and you "accidentally" proposed to Rachel.
我可以先打断你一下吗？
Can I just stop you there for a second?
当有人做这个动作时…
When people do this:
我真的不知道是什么意思
I don't really know what that means.
你刚刚说什么？
You were saying?
我还可以谅解你没有跟瑞秋解释
And I could even understand that you couldn't tell Rachel.
但是为什么你没有告诉我呢？ 你有一整天可以说，你却没有
But why couldn't you tell me? You had all day to,and you didn't.
我知道，我应该说“我很抱歉”
I know. I should've. "I'm sorry."
你用错地方了，乔伊
Not using it right,Joe.
“我很抱歉”
"I'm sorry."
-我要走了 -不，别这样
- I'm gonna go. - No,come on.
-罗斯，我们必须要放下这件事 -把袋子给我
- Ross,we have to get past this. - Give me the bag.
不，我不知道还能怎样 我已经道歉了，现在…
No,I don't know what else to do. I said I'm sorry,now..
现在你应该对我吼叫、咒骂 或是打我
Now you should scream at me or curse me or hit me.
-我不会打你的 -你会比较好过，我也会比较好过
- I'm not gonna hit you. - You'll feel better. I'll feel better.
你知道，你想打我 我从你眼中看得出来
You know you want to,I can see it in your eyes.
-我不想 -有一点
- I don't. - A little bit.
-不想 -有一点
- No. - Little bit.
-不想 -多一点了
- No. - A little bit more.
-把那个袋子给我，把袋子给我 -不，打我，打我
- Give me the bag. Give me the bag. - No,hit me. Hit me.
-给我袋子，给我袋子 -打我
- Give me the bag. I'm not kidding. - Hit me.
-不 -打我，打我，打我！
- No. - Hit me. Hit me. Hit me!
-你闪开了！ -我很抱歉！这是反射动作！
- You ducked! - I'm sorry! It was a reflex!
-喔，天啊！真的好痛！ -我不得不闪哪！
- Oh,my God! This really hurts! - I couldn't help it.
当有拳头要打上你的脸 你会闪啊，瞧
When a fist comes at your face,you duck. Look.
你是怎么搞的？
What is the matter with you?
你应该要闪的！为什么没闪呢？
You were supposed to duck! Why didn't you?
我们去医院的路上再谈
Let's talk on the way to the hospital.
好，是啊，或许当我们过去的时候 他们可以检查一下你的反射神经
Good. Yeah,maybe while we're there,they can check your reflexes.
-再喂她看看 -我已经喂过了
- Try feeding her again. - I already fed her.
我知道，所以我说“再”
I know. That's why I said,"Again!"
你们，我们不可以窝里反，好吗？
You guys,we can't turn on each other,okay?
这正是她想要的
That's just what she wants.
-嗨 -嘿
- Hi. - Hey.
我告诉过你别让她看《母女情深》
I told you you shouldn't have let her watch Terms of Endearment.
-我们可以到外面谈谈吗？ -待在这里
- Can I talk to you outside? - Just stay here.
我要去检查她的尿布 菲比，你要不要一起来呢？
I'm gonna check her diaper. Phoebe,you want to come?
这事与我也有关
I'm kind of part of this.
事实上，这是夫妻两人之间的事
Actually,it's a husband-and-wife kind of thing.
我就知道我应该嫁给钱德的
I knew I should've married Chandler.
-好了，怎么回事呢？ -好的
- Okay,what's up? - Okay.
我们曾经讨论过如果能搬到巴黎 住一年一定会很棒
You know we said it would be fun to move to Paris for a year?
你可以学习法式烹饪 我可以写作…
And you could study French cooking,and I could write..
我们可以在塞纳河畔野餐 去波尔多品酒
and we could picnic along the Seine,and go wine-tasting in Bordeaux.
-是啊 -很好
- Yeah. - Okay.
你知道有些人说土尔沙…
You know how people say that Tulsa..
就像是奥克拉荷马州的巴黎吗？
is the Paris of Oklahoma?
什么？是谁说的？
What? Who says that?
那些从没去过巴黎的人说的
People who have never been to Paris?
-到底是怎么回事？ -我们要搬去土尔沙了
- Well,what's going on? - We're moving to Tulsa.
-你说什么？ -好吧
- Excuse me? - Okay.
我老板的上司，麦肯纳小姐
Ms. McKenna,she kind of works above my boss.
-我想你应该见过她 -我不在乎，快说土尔沙是怎么回事
- I think you actually met her. - Don't care. Get back to Tulsa.
她要我搬到土尔沙 去当那边分公司的总经理
She asked me to move to Tulsa and be president of our office there.
我当时正在打瞌睡，然后 显然我是答应她了
And I was sleeping and apparently said yes.
-奥克拉荷马州的土尔沙？ -抢先之州（奥克拉荷马州的昵称）
- Tulsa,Oklahoma? - The Sooner State.
不管那是什么
Whatever that is.
钱德，我连歌舞剧《奥克拉荷马》 都不想看
Chandler,I don't even want to see the musical Oklahoma.
“喔，美妙的早晨” “坐在马车上头”
"Oh,What a Beautiful Morning," "Surrey With the Fringe on Top"?
你是在说我们要搬去奥克拉荷马 还是说你是同性恋？
Are you trying to tell me we're moving to Oklahoma or that you're gay?
我想我可能躲不掉了
I don't think I can get out of this.
-喔，天啊！ -但是你不知道…
- Oh,my God! - But you don't know..
土尔沙可能会像巴黎一样 你还是可以在奥罗・罗伯特大学…
it could be like Paris. You can still take a cooking class..
上烹饪课
at Oral Roberts University.
好吧，这些都没关系 但至少他们有帮你加薪吧？
All right,not that this matters,but did they at least offer you a huge raise?
没有，但是他们会 帮我们租一台福特福克斯
No. But they are going to lease us a Ford Focus.
-我会试着脱身 -谢谢
- I'll get out of it. - Thank you.
-艾玛是怎么了？ -她误会了
- What is wrong with Emma? - She misunderstood.
她以为是她要搬到土尔沙
She thought she was moving to Tulsa.
请问您现在有空吗？
Ma'am,do you have a minute?
我有些坏消息 我想我不能去土尔沙了
I kind of have some bad news. I don't think I can move to Tulsa.
-什么？ -事实上这是件很好笑的事
- What? - It's a funny story,actually.
我在今天早上的会议上睡着了
I kind of fell asleep in the meeting this morning.
所以当我说我可以搬到土尔沙时 我根本不知道我在说什么
So when I said I'd move to Tulsa,I didn't really know what I was saying.
你睡着了？
You fell asleep?
但那是因为我整晚为会议担心而失眠
But only because I was up all night worried about this meeting.
是不是很好笑呢？
Isn't that funny?
很讽刺，不好笑？好吧
Irony. Not a fan? All right.
好吧，事情是这样的
See,here's the thing.
我回家告诉我老婆土尔沙的事 但是她不想去
I went home and told my wife about Tulsa,and she won't go.
至于我，我爱死土尔沙了 土尔沙是天堂，土尔沙是意大利
See me,I love Tulsa. Tulsa is heaven. Tulsa is ltaly.
拜托别逼我搬去那里
Please don't make me go there.
-钱德，我… -我知道你很不高兴…
- Chandler,I.. - I know that you're upset..
但是我只是… 我真的宁可留在这里
but I just.. I would really rather just stay here.
不是说在你的办公室这里…
Not here in your office..
而是在这里的这间公司
here at the company..
我在这里明显不受欢迎
where I'm rapidly feeling unwelcome.
听着，凯萝 我可以叫你凯萝吗？
No,look,Carol. Can I call you Carol?
我真不应该 因为你的名字是依莲
Why would I when your name is Elaine?
你儿子拍得真棒，雄壮威武
What a great picture of your son. Strapping.
是你女儿的照片，对吧？
That's a picture of your daughter,isn't it?
她真是甜美 我喜欢有坚毅下巴的女孩
Well,she's lovely. I like a girl with a strong jaw.
我会从土尔沙打电话给你的
I'll call you from Tulsa.
嘿，怎样呢？
Hey. So how is it?
-我的拇指断了 -你的拇指？
- I broke my thumb. - Your thumb?
真是奇怪，你确定 你出拳的方式是正确的吗？
That's weird. Are you sure you're punching right?
握拳
Make a fist.
或许等一下好了
Maybe later.
罗斯，我觉得很糟糕
Ross,I feel terrible.
你可以走了 我只要填一些表格就可以了
You know what,you can go. I just have to fill out some forms.
需要我帮忙吗？
You want me to help you with that?
为什么？我看起来像是没办法 使用我的畸形爪子吗？
Why,does it look like I'm having trouble with my misshapen claw?
姓名？
Name?
我知道罗斯 但是那是什么的简称呢？
No,I know Ross. But what's it short for?
你知道的，像是罗素
You know,like Rossell.
或是罗斯多福
Or Rosstrophor.
就是罗斯
Just Ross.
好名字
It's pretty.
-好了，生日呢？ -你知道我生日的
- Okay,date of birth? - You know my birthday.
当然
Sure.
五…九月？
May.. tember?
-十月十八日 -职业？恐龙
- October 18. - Occupation? Dinosaurs.
事实上我是古生物… 恐龙也可以啦
Actually,I'm a paleon.. Dinosaurs is fine.
画图可不行
The drawing is not.
好了，紧急联络人是谁呢？
All right,who do you want as your emergency contact?
-瑞秋，我想应该是吧 -好的，关系呢？
- Rachel,I guess. - Okay. Relationship?
天啊，这可能要花上一点时间
Boy,this could take a while.
-写室友 -少来了
- Just put roommate. - Come on.
你们比室友还更进一步 你们要在一起了，不是吗？
You guys are more than that. You're gonna get together,right?
我不认为我们有要在一起
I don't think that we are.
但是你们应该要在一起的
But you two are supposed to be together.
我也这样想过 但是她却答应要嫁给你
Well,I thought so too. But then she said she'd marry you.
别这样，罗斯 那根本没有什么
Come on,Ross,that didn't mean anything.
她才刚生完吓坏了 要独自扛起一切
She'd just had the baby. She was freaked out about doing it alone.
-任何人求婚，她都会答应的 -是啊，她也是这样说
- She would have said yes to anybody. - Yeah,that's what she said.
-所以呢？ -所以我不想要当“任何人”
- So? - So I don't want to be just anybody.
-哇 -你知道吗？
- Wow. - You know what?
反正这样也比较好
It's better this way anyway.
我不知道我在想什么 再回到之前的关系
I don't know what I was thinking,going down that road again with us.
如果我们纯粹做朋友，只是有个小孩 那事情就会简单多了
It's just much easier if we're just friends who have a kid.
-真的吗？ -是啊
- Really? - Yeah.
-你这样没关系吗？ -是啊，这本来就是我们的计划
- And you're okay with that? - Yes. That's what we always planned.
如果你有计划，你就应该照计划执行
And if you have a plan,you should stick to it.
这就是计划的意义，不是吗？
That's why they call them plans. Hello?
我没事的
I'm fine.
嘿，关于瑞秋…
Hey,for what it's worth..
我不认为你会只是“任何人”而已
with Rachel,I don't think you'll ever be just "anybody."
嘿，你做对了
Hey,there you go.
“谢谢”
"Thanks."
喔，天啊，她哭多久了？
Oh,my God. How long has she been crying?
大约一个星期半
About a week and a half.
看起来你们都已经处理好了 所以我先回去了
Well,it looks like you guys got it under control,so I'm just gonna go.
不好吗？真的？ 一定要有人共享悲惨命运吗？
No? Really? Misery really does love company?
好吧
All right.
-试着用另一种方式抱她 -我已经尽力而为了
- Try holding her a different way. - Look,I'm doing the best I can.
-任何人都欢迎来试试看 -好吧，我来试试看
- Anyone else is welcome to try. - All right,I'll try. Fine.
-好了，好的，好的 -抱去吧
- Yes. Okay. Okay. - Here you go.
嘿，喔，天啊
Hey. Oh,gosh.
这小孩什么都没用！
Nothing works with this child!
天啊，我该怎么办呢？ 我根本照顾不了我自己的孩子
God,what am I gonna do,you guys? I can't even comfort my own baby.
-我是史上最糟的母亲 -不，你只不过是不熟悉罢了
- I'm the worst mother ever. - No,you're just new at this.
你会克服的 想想你第一天上班的时候
You'll get better. Think about your first day at work.
那也不是很简单的事 但你也摆平了啊
That couldn't have been easy,but you figured that out.
是啊，我不认为穿得辣一点 对现在的情况会有帮助！
Yeah,I don't think dressing provocatively is going to help me here!
-天啊，请帮我抱一下 -好，我来抱，来吧
- God,just please take her. - Okay,I'll take her. Come on.
喔，天啊，我要去上一下厕所
Oh,boy,I have to go to the bathroom.
我要去枕头堆里吼一吼
I have to go scream into a pillow.
活泼，活泼的宝贝，活泼的宝贝
Bouncy. Bouncy baby. Bouncy baby.
喔，宝贝，宝贝，喔，宝贝，宝贝
Oh,baby,baby. Oh,baby,baby.
喔，宝贝，宝贝，宝贝
Oh,baby,baby,baby.
我聋了吗？
Have I gone deaf?
有效了，喔，宝贝，宝贝，宝贝 喔，宝贝，宝贝，宝贝
It worked. Oh,baby,baby,baby. Oh,baby,baby,baby.
你在床上一定像个火球！
You must be a fireball in bed!
我不敢相信，她睡着了 我让她睡着了
I can't believe it. She's asleep. I got her to go to sleep.
我真的有神奇的魔力
I have actual magical powers.
我可以听到汽车跟鸟叫声
I can hear traffic and birds.
我又再度听到我脑海中的声音了
I can hear the voices in my head again.
开玩笑的
I'm kidding.
喔，我的天！ 你让她不再哭了！
Oh,my God! You got her to stop crying!
是的，我办到了 我是超级姑姑莫妮卡
Yes,I did. I'm Monica,super aunt.
-你是官方认可的婴儿止哭专家 -是啊，我正是
- You are the official baby-crier stopper. - Yes,I am.
-你永远都不能离开这间公寓了 -什么？
- You're never leaving the apartment. - Say what?
这是你的新工作，日夜兼顾 只要她一哭，我就需要你在这里
That's your new job,day or night. She starts crying,I need you here.
-不，不，不 -很庆幸，你一点都不需要我
- No,no,no. - Thankfully,you don't need me at all.
那么，嘿，超级姑姑 下次见
So okay. Hey,super aunt? See you later.
瑞秋，我们试试看六到八个月
Rachel? Let's give it six to eight months.
好的，听着，我要去睡一下
Okay,so listen,I'm gonna go lay down.
什么？
What?
书上说只要她一睡 我也应该要睡
The book says whenever she's sleeping,I should be sleeping.
所以…
So..
谢谢你
Thank you.
嘿
Hey.
-我们才刚让她睡着 -所以现在不能大声吼叫？
- We just got her to go to sleep. - So there can't be any yelling?
没错
No.
-我们要搬去土尔沙了 -什么？
- We're moving to Tulsa. - What?
我…我听不到
I can't.. I can't hear.
-嘿 -嘿，你去哪了？
- Hey. - Hey. Where have you been?
-发生什么事了？ -我跟乔伊打了起来
- What happened to you? - I had a little thing with Joey.
如果你认为这很糟糕 你应该看看乔伊
If you think this is bad,you should see him.
不，罗斯，这真的很糟
No,Ross,this is not good.
我们必须谈谈乔伊这件事，请坐下
We have to talk about this Joey thing. Please sit.
好了，你必须放下乔伊这件事
All right,you have got to get over this Joey thing.
好吗？我从未真的 想要嫁给乔伊，好吗？
Okay? I never really wanted to marry Joey,okay?
好的
Okay.
你知道我真的很想、很想要什么吗？
You know what I really,really want?
什么？
What,Rach?
我想要睡觉
I wanna sleep.
我想要吃东西，我想要洗澡
I wanna eat. I wanna take a shower.
我是说，她醒来以后 我们又有得忙了
I mean,before she wakes up,and we gotta do this all over again.
-没错 -因为我必须告诉你
- Right. - I mean,because I got news for you.
艾玛，一点都不好带
Emma: not easy.
那正是我在这里的用意
Well,that's what I'm here for.
-你要我去吗？ -不，真的没关系
- You want me to get that? - No,that's really okay.
-莫妮卡？ -来了，来了，来了
- Monica? - Got it,got it,got it,got it.
我一直在想 而且我要告诉你，这不是我的错
I've been thinking about this. And I gotta tell you,it's not my fault.
-那是自然的本能 -你们在说什么？
- It's a natural instinct. - What are you talking about?
好吧，如果我这样你会怎么做？
Okay,what would you do if I did this?